QUDUS OYETOLA

Lagos, Nigeria | +2348091100174 | qudusoyetola@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

PROFILE

Full-stack software engineer with strong skills and relevant experience collaborating with teams to provide digital solutions to business problems using React, Java, JavaScript and other technologies. I build applications with clean, tested and well-documented code and am quick to learn new frameworks and languages. Passionate about software architecture with experience managing projects using a variety of skills such as UX design, network security, BDD and TDD.

SKILLS

Technical

Agile, Scrum, Technical analysis, Software automation, Data structures and Algorithms, Database development, Cross-platform mobile development (iOS & Android), Domain driven and event sourcing architectures, and Software testing.

Tools and Languages

Php, Laravel, Codeigniter, Java, JavaScript, Reactjs, Vue js, HTML 5, CSS, MySQL, Jira, Bitbucket, Github, Amazon AWS, Postman, IntelliJ, Apache, Python, Django

Soft

Self-starter, logical thinker with ability to communicate highly technical information to stakeholders and teams across all levels. Excellent problem-solving skills with active listening skills, trouble-shooter, can-do attitude, and good team player.

EDUCATION

2021 Advance Diploma in Software Engineering (ADSE) - Aptech Computer Education

EXPERIENCE

March 2022 - Current

Software Engineer — FastPlus Innovation

- Working closely with team of engineers to design and implement reusable modularised solutions using the Laravel framework and software engineering principles.
- Creating PhP web security tools to protect clients website from hackers, attacks, and other threats such as SQL Injections, XSS Vulnerabilities, Proxy Visitors, VPN Visitors, TOR Visitors, Spam, and other popular threats.
- Collaborating with the team to develop stable, testable, and maintainable custom apps using Java, PHP, laravel framework for the backend, Vue for the frontend and Postman for API documentation and testing.
- Refactoring the code base of controllers that provide vending of electricity meters and connecting to other third party APIs using separation of concerns design pattern.
- Developing API endpoints to handle clients' CRUD operations using Laravel API and PHP
- Providing on call technical support to ensure live issues are solved and client apps are running at 100% availability.
- Configuring a VPS server, deploying it, and debugging custom web application based on clients requirements.
- Ensuring security and quality assurance best practices are followed through the software development life cycle.
- Ensured code quality across the stack by writing unit and UI tests to identify malfunctions and bugs, before designing and implementing solutions to solve them.
- Liaising with clients and stakeholders to interpret requirements and agree their design and implementation.
- Developing web apps and platform that enables cross border money transfer in an quick and easy way with laravel framework.
- Revising, modularizing and updating legacy code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- A simple Laravel CRUD Loan Application for demo purposes. Where I learn the use of separation of concerns design pattern.
- Creating and designing loan management APIs using Django and MySQL database.
- Building serverless web backend using Amazon API Gateway, AWS Lambda, Amazon SQS, Amazon DynamoDB, and Amazon SNS.
- Designing 3-tier architectures using services like Amazon VPC, Amazon EC2, Amazon RDS with high availability and Elastic Load Balancing following AWS best practices.

April 2021 – April 2022 Software Engineer — Technage, Birmingham

- Collaborated with a distributed team of engineers to deliver several business initiatives for Technage's clients in the UK using tools and technologies such as laravel, react and others. Some of the initiatives I worked on are end to end design and delivery of; A luxury e-commerce platform for a UK based hamper company, web platform for Allied Care home in the UK and Newlife Family, a UK based charity and church.
- Collaborated with the team to build an event management SaaS platform that facilitates seamless processes for creating and managing events of any kind via the web using Laravel PHP framework amongst other web technologies.
- Supported, researched and implemented new coding technologies to increase team productivity
- Repsonsible for revising, modularizing and updating legacy code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Assisting lead developers with various tasks, including creating the project and release plans resulting in learning additional soft skills.
- Improved product development by introducing agile methodologies and best practices to the product teams.
- Created technical requirements, functional specifications, configuration documents, and architecture designs for new and existing projects.

August 2018 – December 2018 Technical Analyst — Mainfaith Digital, Lagos

Coordinated with technical teams to resolve software and hardware problems including user issues remotely and onsite.